<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Metrics | RNA-Puzzles toolkit]]></title>
  <link href="http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/categories/metrics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-22T15:36:43+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chichau Miau]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chichaumiau@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RNAQUA]]></title>
    <link href="http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/rnaqua/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-22T11:48:26+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/rnaqua</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/mantczak/rnaqua.git">RNAQUA (RNA QUality Assessment)</a> is a web service based wrapper of basic RNA comparison metrics. It is a RESTful web service client developed in Java. The tool provides a set of web services initially designed for RNAssess (Lukasiak et al., Nucleic Acids Research, 2015;43(W1):W502-W506. doi:10.1093/nar/gkv557) to support the quality assessment of RNA 3D structures. RNAQUA requires a stable release of JRE 7 (or later) installed on a user workstation with an internet access. Full implementation of the tool is stored on github and maintained by Antczak. The binaries and use cases can be downloaded from <a href="https://github.com/mantczak/rnaqua/releases/download/v1.0/rnaqua-binary.zip">here</a>.
Most important features of RNAQUA:</p>




<ul>
<li>At the input, a user provides RNA 3D structure(s) in PDB format.</li>
<li>Output data are returned in XML format.</li>
<li>RNAQUA allows to compute the following measures:

<ul>
<li>ClashScore,</li>
<li>Root-mean-square deviation (RMSD),</li>
<li>Interaction network fidelity (INF),</li>
<li>Deformation index (DI),</li>
<li>P-value (either for entire RNA 3D structure(s) or for a set of discontinuous 3D substructures).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Two processing modes are available:

<ul>
<li>An analysis of single RNA 3D structure (PDB validation, ClashScore, sequence-based analysis, structure unification),</li>
<li>An analysis of RNA 3D model(s) with respect to the reference structure (RMSD, INF, DI, P-value, Deformation profile, sequence-based differences between structures, multiple models over the reference structure superposition).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Optionally, the user can define alignment between the reference structure and all corresponding RNA 3D model(s) which is helpful if there are differences in sequence, distribution of chains or residue numbering.</li>
</ul>




<p>This metric tool is maintained by <a href="mailto:mantczak@cs.put.poznan.pl">Antczak</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MCQ and LCS-TA]]></title>
    <link href="http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/mcq-and-lcs-ta/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-22T11:48:14+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/mcq-and-lcs-ta</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/tzok/mcq4structures">MCQ (Mean of Circular Quantities)</a> has been first presented in the paper “MCQ4Structures to compute similarity of molecule structures” by Zok et al. (Central European Journal of Operations Research, 2014;22(3):457-474. doi: 10.1007/s10100-013-0296-5).</p>




<p><a href="https://github.com/tzok/mcq4structures">LCS-TA</a> (Longest Continuous Segments in Torsion Angle space) applies a measure first described in the paper “LCS-TA to identify similar fragments in RNA 3D structures” by Wiedemann et al. (BMC Bioinformatics, 2017;18(1):456. doi: 10.1186/s12859-017-1867-6).
A full implementation of both methods can be found on github, maintained by Zok and Wiedemann.</p>




<p>Most important features of both methods / measures:</p>




<ul>
<li><p>MCQ</p>

<ul>
<li>The method applies to a pair of 3D structures and is size independent.</li>
<li>It can be used for a set of structures in all-against-all or all-against-target mode.</li>
<li>It translates typical algebraic representation of a 3D structure into the trigonometric one (a set of torsion angles).</li>
<li>It computes the distance between structures in torsion angle space.</li>
<li>The distance is measured as mean of local distances between the corresponding angles, and provided in degrees.</li>
<li>The measure is sequence independent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>LCS-TA</p>

<ul>
<li>The method applies to a pair of 3D structures and is size independent.</li>
<li>It uses MCQ-based measure for structure comparison.</li>
<li>Within the compared structures, it finds the longest continuous segments which display similarity in torsion angle space.</li>
<li>Two segments are considered similar if their MCQ is below predefined threshold.</li>
<li>The method provides segment length and its position in the structure.</li>
<li>The length of the longest continuous segment is a measure of similarity of two structures.</li>
<li>The method can be run in sequence dependent or sequence independent mode.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>




<p>MCQ is maintained by <a href="mailto:tzok@cs.put.poznan.pl">Zok</a>, while LCS-TA is maintained by <a href="mailto:jwiedemann@cs.put.poznan.pl">Wiedemann</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deformation Profile]]></title>
    <link href="http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/deformation-profile/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-22T11:47:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/deformation-profile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Deformation profile is a metric first discribed in the paper &ldquo;New metrics for comparing and assessing discrepancies between RNA 3D structures and models.&rdquo; (RNA. 2009 Oct;15(10):1875-85. doi: 10.1261/rna.1700409. )</p>




<p>A full implementation can be found at <a href="https://github.com/RNA-Puzzles/DeformationProfile">github</a>, maintained by <a href="mailto:zmiao@ebi.ac.uk">Chichau</a></p>




<p>RNA-Puzzles Assessment consider all the &ldquo;<a href="https://github.com/RNA-Puzzles/BasicAssessMetrics">Basic Assessment Metrics</a>&rdquo;, <a href="https://github.com/RNA-Puzzles/DeformationProfile">Deformation profile</a> and &ldquo;<a href="https://github.com/tzok/mcq4structures">Mean of Circular Quantities</a>&rdquo;.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic Assessment Metrics]]></title>
    <link href="http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/basic-assessment-metrics/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-22T11:24:57+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://chichaumiau.github.io/rnapuzzlestoolkit/blog/2018/07/22/basic-assessment-metrics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The basic metrics of RNA 3D structure comparison include:</p>




<ul>
<li>Root Mean Square Deviation (RMSD)</li>
<li>P value</li>
<li>Deformation Index</li>
<li>Interaction Network fidelity

<ul>
<li>this metric can be measured by different types of contacts, including:</li>
<li>all contacts</li>
<li>Watson-Crick interaction</li>
<li>non-Waston-Crick interaction</li>
<li>stacking</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>




<p>All of these metrics have been implemented in <a href="https://github.com/RNA-Puzzles/BasicAssessMetrics">Basic Assess Metrics</a> (author: <a href="mailto:zmiao@ebi.ac.uk">Chichau</a>)</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
